# LEIF HUHN

Chicago, IL 60660 leif.n.huhn@gmail.com (415) 583-5685

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Site-reliability engineer with over 19 years of experience in a wide variety of technologies and platforms. Strengths in managing Elasticsearch, HBase/Hadoop, and customer facing web apps in Kubernetes, AWS EC2, and other clouds. Strong programming skills and experience with large codebases.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## CenturyLink Cloud

2015 - 2019

Senior Lead Software Developer

REMOTE Bellevue, WA / St. Louis, MO

- · Managed cloud services in both AWS and CenturyLink cloud.
- · Used SaltStack to manage Linux, Hadoop, HBase, Zookeeper, Kafka, and Elastic Search.
- · Deployed Master-Master replication in order to perform blue-green upgrade deployment of critical database infrastructure.
- · Deployed Consul in multi-datacenter mesh in order to support application failover.
- · Used Bash and Go scripting for various system administration purposes.
- · Created a virtual firewall product for CenturyLink's cloud using NSX Edge firewalling.
- · Migrated features from a monolithic control portal to microservices running on Kubernetes.

#### Riverbed Technology

2010 - 2015

Team Lead

San Francisco, CA

- · Mentored junior coders.
- · Oversaw maintenance of critical pieces of our testing infrastructure.
- · Conceived of, collaboratively designed, and oversaw development of an automated program "Rack-and-Roll," greatly simplifying the process of adding new hardware into the lab.
- · Created system to power down unused testing machines, saving power, cooling, and money.
- · Automated VMWare vCenter to automate the installation and testing of VMs.
- · Troubleshot various DHCP, TFTP, and PXE networking problems using Cisco, Force10 hardware.
- · Troubleshot problems with internal appliance manufacturing, including bugs in the unreleased product, bugs in the build system, hardware problems, user error, networking problems, service outages, etc.
- · Used puppet to automate system administration tasks.
- · Refactored testing codebase for greater maintainability.
- · Made OO design decisions for future direction of testing codebase.

#### Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

2003 - 2010

 $System\ Administrator$ 

Berkeley, CA

- · Installed, maintained, and updated Linux and Windows servers providing critical infrastructure (mail, web, dns, nfs, mysql, iptables, RAID, LVM, and ssh).
- · Reduced our server footprint by 60% by migrating applications from legacy versions of BSD and SunOS to Linux, thereby saving on licensing costs.

- · Managed remote servers for multiple law firms. Worked with system administrators from client companies to resolve networking problems.
- · Transitioned our systems to 64-bit to allow processing of larger datasets.
- · Evaluated server workloads and made purchasing decisions.
- · Hired and oversaw contractors to upgrade data and phone wiring.
- · Used Nagios to provide 24/7/365 monitoring of critical services.
- · Responsible for migrating data obtained through legal discovery into our systems (i.e. from Oracle, PostreSQL, etc).
- · Automated backup processes.

### Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

Web Developer

2001 - 2003Berkeley, CA

- $\cdot$  Developed Model-View-Controller web framework with a MySQL backend tailored for the specific needs of the company.
- · Created websites to allow hundreds of paralegals from around the country to work together to interview thousands of plaintiffs in large class action lawsuits.
- · Oversaw and trained junior web developers.
- · Wrote Perl programs to process data in legacy formats.

# Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission

Web Developer

1999 - 2000 Tallahassee, FL

- · Developed data aware client side web applications.
- · Increased productivity through the creation of a system for dynamically tracking bird migration patterns thereby freeing an analyst from writing weekly reports.
- · Managed IIS web servers.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Perl, Python, C/C++, Java, Go.
- · XML, HTML, SQL
- · NoSQL databases, Hadoop, HBase, Zookeeper, Kafka, Consul, Couchbase
- · RabbitMQ, Redis
- · Apache, IIS
- · MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQL Server
- · Cisco IOS, Force10 FTOS
- · Puppet, Salt, Ansible, Linux, BSD
- · Sendmail, DNS
- · Icinga, Nagios, Kibana, Graphite, Prometheus

- · RAID, LVM, NFS
- · tcpdump, wireshark
- · Unix Scripting: bash, expect
- · Windows Deployment, Hyper-V, cygwin, Power-shell
- · OS X
- · VMWare ESX, VMWare NSX, vCenter, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, KVM
- · LATEX

#### **EDUCATION & HOBBIES**

- · University of California, Berkeley, CA
  - Bachelors Degree in Physics
- · Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL
  - Completed University Honors Program. GPA: 3.9
- · Conversational in American Sign Language, some knowledge of Spanish, French, and Japanese